JIM: Previously on Gotham...
My name is Volk. My brother, Jacob.
We are called "the Whisper Gang."
BRUCE: Those men were
willing to kill for this key.
- But what does it open?
- A safe.
Inside, there is a device that
we believe can destroy them.
They call themselves
"The Court of Owls."
Isabella was murdered.
Her brake lines were cut!
And I know who did it.
You can stop the blade from being
released, if you click this button.
It will send a
fatal jolt to Butch.
Hey, Butch? You're sweet.
No!
- You really didn't kill her?
- No!
Guilty!
The lab analyzing Alice Tetch's
blood has developed a test.
You're kidding.
Don Falcone, please,
we'll pull your car around.
JIM: Carmine's not the
target. You are. Get down!
Why are you coming after me?
(CHOKING) You know why.
Why are you
trying to kill my son?
We will expect your
assistance when called on.
Until then, your son is safe.
At least from us.
Why does it feel like we
keep saying goodbye?
Maybe it's all we have left.
Or we just haven't
done it properly yet.
Goodbye, James Gordon.
MARIO: She loves
him. She loves him.
You lost?
She loves me!
Hey.
(BEEPS)
(DOOR OPENS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
I'm getting married tomorrow.
Congratulations.
You know, people always
talk about love at first sight.
I never believed it.
But the moment
I saw her, I knew.
Yeah.
So what do you do?
I'm a hematologist
at Gotham Bio-Lab.
You aren't working on
that blood virus, are you?
From... What's her
name? Tetch? Alice Tetch?
Uh, my fiancée is with
the police department.
- She's the medical examiner on the case.
- Oh.
Yes.
She said you had come
up with a test for the virus.
I really can't talk about it.
She almost married someone else.
I think her ex still hopes
she'll come running back.
Not gonna happen.
- Ah! (GRUNTS)
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
MARIO: She loves
him. She loves him.
She loves him.
You hear me, Jim?
I won't let you have her.
- (SCREAMING)
- (SKULL CRACKLING)
(SQUELCHING)
(LAUGHING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Volk is dead?
We found his and Dmitry's
bodies early this morning.
They were killed by
Talon, the Court's assassin.
I'll say that changes
things a bit, doesn't it?
How? You possess a
key. The key opens a safe.
Inside the safe is an object that
can bring down the Court of Owls.
None of these has changed.
If this assassin
saw us with Volk...
That means the
Court already knows
that you're breaking
your deal, Master Bruce.
I wish we knew for certain.
Yeah, well, I wish we knew for
certain what was in that blinking safe
or how far we can trust
this little Whisper Gang front.
Now ask yourself this.
Is bringing down the
Court really worth the risk?
The Court of Owls has
taken over my company.
Threatened people I care about,
and is likely responsible
for my parents' deaths.
What's our next step?
- (INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
- (CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
I'm giving this one to Alvarez.
No.
I told you to take the day off.
I know.
You do know I'm acting
captain now, right?
Yeah.
Jim, there will be another
dead body tomorrow.
Seriously, take the day.
Go fishing, get drunk.
Harvey, this is my job. Lee
getting married doesn't change that.
Take a look at this guy's head.
Whoa, what's that
coming out of his ear?
JIM: His skull was crushed.
Like someone squeezed
it from either side.
Can you imagine the
strength needed to do that?
I gotta tell you,
my first thought.
- (SCOFFS) Oh, no.
- Barnes.
Stop it! Barnes had the
virus. He's at Arkham.
That story's over. This
is what I was afraid of.
Wallet's here, but the killer took a
badge or something from around his neck.
Your emotions are all stirred.
You're seeing things
that aren't really there.
This is just a classic case
of wrong place, wrong time.
One man takes another man's
skull in his bare hands and crushes it.
I see it all the time.
Receipt from the cafeteria
at Gotham Bio-Lab.
Where Alice Tetch's
blood is being tested.
Crap.
I'm gonna swing by.
Finish up here, will you?
Sure, Jim, happy to oblige.
No rest for the wicked.
Relax.
I'm not here to get revenge
for you lopping off Tabby's paw.
Though I am surprised
to find you back at work
and not tracking down who
really did kill your lady love.
That's because you
don't see the full picture.
The mayor has many enemies.
These enemies understand that I
am a fundamental part of this operation.
They weaken me, they weaken him.
That was clearly the
intent of killing Isabella.
Also, I have spies
all over the city.
Soon enough, whoever killed
Isabella will reveal themselves,
and I will strike.
Poor blind baby.
It's always hardest to see
what's right under our noses.
(COUGHS) Penguin!
Did you just
fake-cough "Penguin"?
(CHUCKLING)
Needless to say, that is
absurd on a number of levels.
Really?
All a crime requires is
means, motive, and opportunity.
And your beaky little buddy certainly
has the means and opportunity.
But no motive.
Oh, I would say he had
the oldest motive in the book.
Rich men want it, wise men
know it, the poor all need it.
Love. What does
that have to do...
And the penny drops.
You are suggesting
that Oswald is in love with me.
That is ridiculous.
I know. I mean, personally,
I find you a bit of a cold fish.
But Ozzie saw you being taken
away from him by that bookish vixen.
And...
(IMITATES ENGINE RUNNING)
Oh, no!
Hmm.
No.
In fact, I'm beginning to wonder
what your motive is in all this.
That's for later.
Right now, I just
wanna see justice
for that poor sweet girl.
Ms. Kean, I need you
to understand two things.
One, Oswald did
not kill Isabella.
And two, he is
not in love with me.
Are you so certain?
Don't you owe it
to her to find out?
Let me know how it goes.
The Court of Owls maintains a
number of buildings in Gotham.
This one is rarely occupied.
But always well-guarded.
And there are two alarms.
The first covers points of entry.
Last week, we managed to
disarm one of the windows.
Once inside, the front door can be
opened using a code that we possess.
The second alarm is in the
basement, in the room with the safe.
The floor is fitted
with infrared sensors.
You must cross it on a rope.
I have trained for this.
You will give me the key you
found, and I will retrieve the object.
But you still don't know
what the object is, right?
Only that the Court
protects it. Fears it.
And that with Talon
hunting us, we have no time.
Right, so let's go
through this again.
What'd you decide?
We're gonna break in today.
We can't wait any longer.
- You okay?
- Fine.
Just hungry.
JIM: GCPD.
A guy named Ryan
Pfeffer work here?
Uh, yeah. He's sub-level
3. What, he in trouble?
He was killed last night. I
need to talk to his colleagues.
You guys keep track of
when keycards are used?
Uh, yeah.
All right.
If anybody uses his, call me.
Sure, but his was
used 20 minutes ago.
He hasn't logged out.
Call the police. Now.
(GRUNTING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Jim, Jim.
You're ahead of schedule. Our
paths weren't meant to cross just yet.
But I'm not gonna kill you yet.
I do that, you
become the martyr.
And she'll carry you
in her heart forever.
No. Before I kill you,
she has to hate you.
And she will.
Come find me, Jim.
So you didn't get a look at the
guy. And he's not on the cameras.
We might get something
off the prints, but...
Doubtful, if he was smart enough
to avoid the cameras. I'm good.
He seems to have been interested in
the research into Alice Tetch's blood.
Pfeffer's office was ransacked
and their files were missing.
So someone else is infected
with the virus? That's just great.
It isn't you, is it? Because that
sure would make things easy.
No. It's not me. What's
that on your hand?
"Arkham." I didn't write it.
Okay, let's all just calm down.
So the virus-infected
killer wrote on your hand.
He wants you to go to Arkham.
Barnes is in Arkham.
No. It's not about Barnes.
- Jim, you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
(DOOR ALARM BUZZES)
- Hello, Jervis.
- James.
What an unexpected pleasure.
Someone else is infected
with your sister's blood.
You don't say!
And I've been thinking, it's possible
she infected them accidentally.
Yes, possible, possible.
But your reaction
tells me you knew.
So, you infected them after
you stole your sister's blood.
But you stayed quiet, waiting
for them to show symptoms.
Well, that would be darn
sneaky of me, wouldn't it?
I need the name.
(CHUCKLING) You need the name.
So, I've been quiet
about it all this time,
and now I'm going to help you,
because we're such good friends?
Because I can make your
life here very uncomfortable.
More uncomfortable than
having Captain Barnes next door
screaming, "Guilty!"
all hours of the night?
Give me the name!
(CHUCKLING) Oh, James, I would love
to see what Alice's virus would do to you.
The beast in you is right
there, so desperate to get out.
And I know of whom you
speak, oh, yes, indeed.
I stabbed him and pricked
him and caused him to bleed.
But nothing you can say,
no words you might possess can
pry from me the smallest guess.
For this game is my game.
I say when it's done.
And right now I'm
having too much fun.
You wanna play a game, Jervis?
Fine. Let's play a game.
Whoever you infected
has some sort of plan.
I want you to tell me
the name of this man.
Well, James, I have
to give that effort an F.
And can you really
imagine that...
Two are dead. More may die soon.
This isn't a game,
give me his name.
You'll only know his
name when it's too late,
when the one you love
has been murdered by hate.
Guard! Take me to my cell!
- What do you mean "the one that I love"?
- Guard!
Give me his name, Tetch. Give me
his name! Or you share the blame!
Nothing! Nothing!
I'll tell you naught!
His name shall be
neither spoken nor taught.
He'll cut, and he'll crush,
and the blood will run thick!
Though from healer to killer
is no easy trick! (GROANS)
"Healer to killer."
He's a doctor.
Oh, my God.
You'll never stop him, James!
He'll kill, and he'll
kill, and he'll kill!
This is Jim Gordon. Get me
Dr. Mario Calvi immediately.
On my damn
authority! Just do it!
ALFRED: I take it you're off.
(SIGHS)
When we were casing that place, I
got a feeling we were being watched.
And if this Court of
Owls is all you say,
they're not gonna be too cool
with Bruce breaking their deal.
That's very true.
But Master Bruce knows the Court
will catch up with him sooner or later.
And if he has the opportunity to take
them out, then he will take them out.
That's a big "if."
Especially when your stupid job
is supposed to be protecting him.
My stupid job, miss,
is to make sure that he grows
up to be the man he's meant to be.
Still.
Kind of a punk move for him to make a deal
with the people who killed his parents.
Yeah, well, you
understand this then.
He only did what he did to
protect the people he cares about.
For you.
And it cost him dearly.
Are you serious? Arresting Don
Falcone's son on his wedding day?
I had no choice.
He's got the virus.
Do you really think Lee
Thompkins, Dr. Lee Thompkins,
wouldn't know if her
own fiancé had the virus?
How long did Barnes
have it and hide it?
Tetch must have infected him that
night in the hospital when he dosed me.
- It would explain things.
- Like what?
Mario hitting me at
the engagement party.
You know what also
would explain that?
You telling Tetch
to shoot his fiancée.
You should've seen his face when
those assassins attacked us, his rage.
He was being
attacked by assassins!
What was I supposed to do,
Harvey? Wait until he kills again?
Till he hurts Lee?
You were supposed to wait
until you had enough proof.
And why would Tetch
infect Mario in the first place?
To hurt me.
Okay, let's say you're right.
Let's say that Mario is infected.
So he crushes some guy's
skull. He breaks into the lab.
He attacks you and then he
writes "Arkham" on your hand?
Why would he
want you to find him?
I don't know.
He doesn't have the virus.
What? No, no, no. Run it again.
I ran it three
times. He's clean.
I could've told you that.
But, hey, I'm glad it's official.
Dr. Calvi, on
behalf of the GCPD,
I just want to apologize for any
inconvenience or embarrassment
this may have caused you.
No need. Living with Lee, I understand
the pressures you're all under.
But if you'll excuse me, I
have a wedding to attend.
Jim.
I understand this is
a tough day for you.
But no hard feelings.
The test. That's why
you broke into the lab.
To find out how to beat it.
- But why?
- Jim...
I know you have the
virus. I'm gonna prove it.
And I promise you
will never marry Lee.
But she didn't say anything?
She said she thought
we were being watched.
Personally I think
she's just got the jitters.
She can't still be mad
- I told Ivy she was my girlfriend.
- (GROANS) Oh.
It just slipped out. She can
call herself whatever she wants.
Fascinating as I find this tale of
young unrequited love is, Master Bruce,
please can we just
concentrate on the task at hand?
Do you have the key?
Excellent.
Alfred, you know when we
get this thing, whatever it is,
the Whispers are gonna
try to take it from us.
Well, to be honest,
Master Bruce,
it's not the Whispers
I'm worried about.
(GASPING AND CHOKING)
And have we made any headway
on the waterfront negotiations?
ED: I've spoken
with the union leader.
He agreed to our offer.
So those photos can
go back in the vault.
- They were quite saucy, weren't they?
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
And how about the...
Your approval for the new casino
should come through tomorrow.
Demolition can begin right away.
Ed, I cannot tell you how good it
is to see you back to your old self.
Just one last signature.
This is your resignation.
Isabella's death has altered
things and I can't continue...
No! Ed, I will
not let you leave!
It is not in your best interest.
You have to stay busy.
How can I say this?
We're friends.
- Aren't we, Oswald?
- Huh?
Of course!
Since the accident...
And I never thought
that this could happen.
I've had the desire to become
more than employer-employee.
More than friends.
I have been feeling the same.
I didn't wanna mention it
because of all the
awfulness about Isabelle.
- Isabella.
- (GULPS)
But...
One cannot deny love.
(GASPS)
What is it? What's wrong?
There...
There's been a misunderstanding.
I was going to propose
that we become partners.
Business partners.
Partners.
- Then...
- Excuse me.
(DOOR OPENS)
Lee? You here? It's Jim!
MARIO: Hello, Jim.
I saw you left Lee a message.
I, uh, accidentally took
her phone this morning.
She's not here, by the way.
- Drink?
- No, thanks.
How'd you pass the test?
Because I don't have the virus.
Or do I?
You're gonna arrest me, Jim?
You wanna look even more
like the paranoid ex-lover?
I'll only pass the test again.
We'll find out how you
beat it. Only a matter of time.
Let's say I do have the virus.
How would I have gotten it?
From Tetch. When he
dosed me with hallucinogen.
JERVIS: Dr. Calvi, I'd like
you to meet my sister, Alice.
With Barnes, the virus
stoked his anger at the guilty.
What dark part of me
has it brought to life?
Jealousy.
You're afraid of losing Lee.
If that's true,
that means the woman
we both know you still love
is gonna marry a lunatic
who'll do anything to keep her.
Are you sure you
don't want that drink?
What I wanna know is
why you put me on your trail.
What are you after?
Let me give you a hint.
You see, what keeps me up at night
is not the thought that you love her.
It's the thought that a
part of her still loves you.
Well, in that
case, let's find her.
Let her decide if
she's gonna marry you.
Yeah, I don't think so.
The virus made you strong,
not bulletproof. Let's go.
You know what, Jim,
with all this virus talk,
you keep forgetting one thing.
I'm still Carmine Falcone's son.
You know Victor.
(GRUNTS)
Hi-ho.
JIM: Victor, were
you listening to him?
He has the same
virus as Barnes had!
What's that? Oh,
no. I wasn't listening.
- You have to let me go.
- Uh-huh?
- Does Falcone know you're here?
- Wait.
Wait.
You're free to go, Jim.
(BULLET CLATTERS)
I'll keep this.
I don't understand.
I was only supposed to keep you
until the big hand was on
nine and the little hand...
My mag. Now.
Sorry, Jim.
But hey, give the
bride a kiss for me.
(GRUNTS)
I asked.
And it is with great pleasure
that I present this award
to Mr. Kyle Davis for
his magnificent book,
Gotham's Sewers:
an Oral History.
Looks just fascinating.
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
Thank you.
Oh, you're too kind. I love...
- (GRUNTS)
- (SCREAMS)
(ALL CLAMORING)
(APPLAUSE CONTINUES)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Ed.
I was worried when you ran off.
That I might have upset you.
Can't we just pretend
that nothing happened?
Just go back to the
way things were?
You are the best
friend I've ever had.
I don't wanna lose you.
(BREATHING RAGGEDLY)
Please.
You're my best
friend as well, Oswald.
Remember that.
Jim, what are you doing here?
Are you okay?
Where's Mario?
He's out at the church.
We're about to get married!
You can't marry him.
Oh, my God.
- Just give us a minute.
- Yeah.
(DOOR OPENS)
Listen to me. And I know
how this is gonna sound.
You think that he
has Alice Tetch's virus.
- He told you.
- Yes.
And he told me that you had him
arrested today. On our wedding day.
And you had Lucius give him the
test three times. And he passed.
- What's wrong with you?
- He cheated the test, Lee.
I don't know how. But he did.
Tetch infected him
that night in the hospital.
You went to see
Tetch, didn't you?
Yes.
Jim, don't you see? Tetch is
planting ideas in your head.
- No.
- Don't you remember?
- He's done this before.
- No. This isn't like that.
Okay, what is more likely?
That Tetch is planting ideas
in your head to screw with you,
or that Mario has Alice's virus?
Lee, you cannot marry him!
Mario said that you would
never let us be happy.
I thought he was
overreacting. But he's right.
Tetch or not, you are obsessed.
Let it go!
This is what he wanted.
What are you talking about?
This. Me coming here.
That's why he
put me on his trail.
He got the test so he
could find out how to beat it,
he had me arrest him so
I'd look like a jealous ex.
That's why Zsasz let
me go, so I'd race here.
And finally push you away.
Oh, Jim.
I say this as someone
who cares about you.
Get help.
I love you.
I've never stopped.
I should've come to see you
as soon as I got out of prison,
but I couldn't.
I was ashamed.
I felt I had to
set things right.
But I did finally come, Lee.
I saw you through
the window with him.
You were smiling.
You looked happy.
I couldn't bring
myself to go in.
I've regretted it
every day since.
Please.
Don't marry him.
After the wedding,
Mario and I are leaving Gotham.
I'll never see you again.
- Lee...
- Damn you.
For telling me this now!
(SOBBING) You come in here
with these crazy accusations,
and when I don't
believe you, you pull this?
How dare you? (GRUNTS)
Don't you see?
- He wants you to hate me.
- Well, he succeeded.
- Get the hell out of here!
- No!
(SIGHS) Fine.
Carmine.
Can you please help
Detective Gordon find the exit?
Certainly.
And if you're ready, my dear...
I am.
PRIEST: Do you, Leslie,
take Mario to be your husband?
I do.
(GRUNTING)
And do you, Mario, take
Leslie to be your wife?
I do.
PRIEST: I now pronounce
you husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. and Mrs. Calvi.
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
Well, I think it's
safe to admit that
our foreign friends are a
no-show, Master Bruce.
It was a right
dodgy plan, anyway.
- Where are you going?
- That would be home.
Alfred, this is our only
shot to take down the Court.
Yeah, well, you don't know that,
do you? I mean, it was a moot point.
Anyway. I mean, walking across the entire
length of a room on a bloody tightrope?
I can do it. I did it.
Yeah. Three times out of 20. I
counted. No, thank you very much.
I can do it.
Oh, that's bloody
marvelous, isn't it?
Hey?
Right. The deal is this. You
stay on comms, at all times.
If I order "abort," you
abort. Is that clear?
- I need my head examined. I really do.
- (SELINA SCOFFS)
(ZIPPING UP)
What?
Just wondering.
Does this mean
you are my girlfriend?
Shut up.
So, I thought if I were Mario,
how would I beat the test?
Well, the test looks for
this one marker in the blood.
But that marker can be masked by
an abundance of certain other drugs.
The two most easily
available, Cloracinamine and...
Lucius, just get to the point.
Mario's blood came back off
the charts for Cloracinamine.
Alvarez, get a unit on Lee
Thompkins and Dr. Mario Calvi!
And don't let 'em
out of your sight!
This isn't proof that
Mario killed those men.
No, but it's enough
for a search warrant.
Now I gotta go find Jim Gordon.
GOON: Don't mess with Falcone!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(CAR ENGINE REVVING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORN BLARING)
Hey.
(GRUNTS)
(BEEPING)
All right. Straight to the safe room.
I'm gonna check the rest of the house.
- Go on.
- This way.
Not exactly hiding it.
There's no point.
The floor is alarmed.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Don't let go.
- (GASPS)
- (GRUNTS)
(STRAINING)
(LOCK CLICKS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (ALARM BLARING)
(GRUNTS)
- (GRUNTS)
- Come on!
Out the way you came!
- Let's go!
- No!
(GRUNTING)
No!
Ah!
(GRUNTING)
(CHOKES)
We have to leave.
And who exactly are you?
You're the one who's
been following us.
Hey.
You know her?
That's my mom.
Now can we get out of here?
You're bloody right.
- Found it! In his trash. Cloracinamine.
- (CAMERA SHUTTERS CLICKING)
Oh, yes.
We got him. Tell Alvarez.
That was Alvarez. Lee and Mario
snuck out of the reception. He lost them.
(TABITHA GRUNTING)
I can't even hold a knife. I
swear, when I see Nygma...
We'll kill him
together. Real slow.
How sweet.
You son of a bitch!
Hear him out. Please.
I don't want to kill him.
I want to destroy him!
I want to take away
everything that he loves!
I want to make him
despised!
What're you talking about?
Penguin.
- He killed the librarian.
- What?
And you cut off my hand?
I assume you want something.
With Penguin gone, the
underworld will need a new leader.
I think it's time Gotham
had a woman's touch.
The crime families
will never follow you.
Well, that's where you come in.
You know the families in and out.
Not to mention you're
a whiz at strategy.
Think about it, Ed.
Your brains, their brawn,
my... Me.
We could make quite a team.
We destroy Penguin first.
'Course.
But there is one
thing you need to do.
Okay.
(CLEARS THROAT)
- I'm sorry about your hand.
- Apology not accepted.
Well, we'll work
on that. Drinks!
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
Hey.
Thank you.
Thank you. For letting
us leave that party early.
Mmm. Of course. I
wanted to. I love this house.
It's my father's refuge. Not
many people know about it.
I know Gordon came to
the church, talked to you.
It was just like you
said. (SCOFFS)
He said you had the
virus. He was obsessed.
And what did you say?
That after the wedding we
would be leaving Gotham.
And I would never see him again.
Is that it?
What are you asking me?
I'm asking
if there's any part of
you, however small,
that still has feelings for him.
And I swear I will
never ask you again.
A part of me will
always care for him.
But I married you.
I love you.
That's all I needed to know.
- Where are they?
- GOON: Don Falcone, he just...
Where are they?
You don't give up, do you?
Your son has
Alice Tetch's virus.
He's killed two people we know
of. Every cop in this city is after him.
Where is he?
You knew?
That Mario had the
same virus as Barnes? No.
I knew he was in danger,
but I didn't know why.
I never suspected this.
You're saying the attacks
on Mario, the car bomb...
It's because of the virus?
How is that possible?
Who knew he had it?
I can't tell you that.
I'll send my men
to bring Mario in.
You think I'd trust Lee's
life with these two goons?
Tell me where they are.
If I do that, you'll kill
him. I know you, James.
Mario is my son.
There is nothing and no
one more valuable to me.
And if he does have this
sickness, he needs help.
And if he kills Lee, he'll cross a
line he'll never come back from.
Even if he's cured,
knowing that will destroy him.
I'm your only hope.
Still, I'll send my men.
You mean these two?
(BOTH GROAN)
Anyone else you want to send?
Swear that you'll
bring him in alive.
I swear. Now, where are they?
MARIO: She loves
him. She loves him.
She loves him.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
She loves him. She loves him.
Lee!
DR. THOMPKINS: Jim?
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
English -SDH